<section title="Introduction" anchor="introduction">

	<section title="Purpose" anchor="intro.purpose">
		<t>
		The "Instant Satisfaction by Obscure Unstable Protocol" (InstantSOUP) is an application-level protocol for local massage exchange. The protocol was developped during a telematik project at Karlsruhe Institute of Technology (KIT) in year 2012. InstantSOUP connects the application user to a lobby in his network where he can find other users and chatrooms. Therefrom it provides multiple basic chat and chatroom functions, many of whom are there to communicate with each other.
		</t>
		<t>
		The protocol is devided in two major concepts. First the lobby which is realized by peer to peer transferring a message to all recipients simultaneously. It helps to exchange informations about users and channels in PDUs and to ensure discovery.
		The second part is a client server based architecture to ensure the massage transmission from user to user. The UDPs contain information about which users are destinated to become a message and what the message will contain.
		</t>
		<t>
		"Features:"
		</t>
	</section>

	<section title="Requirements" anchor="intro.requirements">
		<t>
		   The key words "MUST", "MUST NOT", "REQUIRED", "SHALL", "SHALL NOT",
		   "SHOULD", "SHOULD NOT", "RECOMMENDED", "MAY", and "OPTIONAL" in this
		   document are to be interpreted as described in RFC 2119 <xref target="RFC2119"/>.
		</t>
		<t>
		   An implementation is not compliant if it fails to satisfy one or more
		   of the MUST or REQUIRED level requirements for the protocols it
		   implements. An implementation that satisfies all the MUST or REQUIRED
		   level and all the SHOULD level requirements for its protocols is said
		   to be "unconditionally compliant"; one that satisfies all the MUST
		   level requirements but not all the SHOULD level requirements for its
		   protocols is said to be "conditionally compliant."
		</t>
	</section>

	<section title="Terminology" anchor="intro.terminology">
		<t>
		   This specification uses a number of terms to refer to the roles
		   played by participants in, and objects of, InstantSOUP.
		</t>
		<t>
		  <iref item="lobby"/>
		  <?rfc needLines="4"?>lobby
		  <list>
			<t>
			  lobby description
			</t>
		  </list>
		</t>
	</section>

</section>
