<section title="Introduction" anchor="introduction">

	<section title="Purpose" anchor="intro.purpose">
		<t>
            The "Instant Satisfaction by Obscure Unstable Protocol" (InstantSOUP) is an application-level protocol for local message exchange.
            The protocol was developed during a telematics project at Karlsruhe Institute of Technology (KIT) during the course of the winter semester 2011/2012.
            InstantSOUP is responsible for connecting the user to a lobby in his/her local area network. Here the user is able to find other participants and chat rooms.
            It provides basic chat functionality which is described thoroughly below <xref target="intro.features"/>.
		</t>
		<t>
            The InstantSOUP protocol is divided into two major concepts, namely a lobby and a client-server architecture.
            The lobby <xref target="intro.terminology.lobby"/> allows the user <xref target="intro.terminology.user"/>
            to communicate with different participants <xref target="intro.terminology.participant"/> without explicitly joining a server <xref target="intro.terminology.server"/>.
            The client-server architecture, on the other hand, allows the user to host a server which ultimately offers
            different user-created channels<xref target="intro.terminology.channel"/> on which participants can join and chat.
		</t>
	</section>

    <section title="Features" anchor="intro.features">
    		<t>
                features
    		</t>
    </section>


	<section title="Requirements" anchor="intro.requirements">
		<t>
		   The key words "MUST", "MUST NOT", "REQUIRED", "SHALL", "SHALL NOT",
		   "SHOULD", "SHOULD NOT", "RECOMMENDED", "MAY", and "OPTIONAL" in this
		   document are to be interpreted as described in RFC 2119 <xref target="RFC2119"/>.
		</t>
		<t>
		   An implementation is not compliant if it fails to satisfy one or more
		   of the MUST or REQUIRED level requirements for the protocols it
		   implements. An implementation that satisfies all the MUST or REQUIRED
		   level and all the SHOULD level requirements for its protocols is said
		   to be "unconditionally compliant"; one that satisfies all the MUST
		   level requirements but not all the SHOULD level requirements for its
		   protocols is said to be "conditionally compliant."
		</t>
	</section>

	<section title="Terminology" anchor="intro.terminology">
        <t>
           This specification uses a number of terms to refer to the roles
           played by participants in, and objects of, InstantSOUP.
        </t>
        <t>
          <iref item="peer"/>
          <?rfc needLines="4"?>Peer
          <list>
            <t>
              peer description
            </t>
          </list>
        </t>
        <t>
          <iref item="node"/>
          <?rfc needLines="4"?>Node
          <list>
            <t>
              node description
            </t>
          </list>
        </t>
        <t>
          <iref item="channel"/>
          <?rfc needLines="4"?>Channel
          <list>
            <t>
              channel description
            </t>
          </list>
        </t>
        <t>
          <iref item="client"/>
          <?rfc needLines="4"?>Client
          <list>
            <t>
              client description
            </t>
          </list>
        </t>
        <t>
          <iref item="server"/>
          <?rfc needLines="4"?>Server
          <list>
            <t>
              server description
            </t>
          </list>
        </t>
        <t>
          <iref item="user"/>
          <?rfc needLines="4"?>User
          <list>
            <t>
              user description
            </t>
          </list>
        </t>
        <t>
          <iref item="participant"/>
          <?rfc needLines="4"?>Participant
          <list>
            <t>
               Participant description
            </t>
          </list>
        </t>
        <t>
          <iref item="pdu"/>
          <?rfc needLines="4"?>Protocol Data Unit
          <list>
            <t>
                Protocol Data Unit description
            </t>
          </list>
        </t>

	</section>

</section>